<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<ce>
  <page>
    <articles>
      <article title="Background">
        <paragraph>
          <text>
            <![CDATA[
            <p>The Chinese Language and Talent Competition was established in 2010 by Culture Exploration of Greater China, 
               which is a non-profit organization dedicated to promoting a better understanding of greater China and Chinese culture by 
               offering cultural learning opportunities to local American educators. Under their spirit of cultural communication, 
               the CE built the Chinese Language and Talent Competition as the platform where people integrated Chinese language and 
               culture into local culture and life.</p>
            <br/>
            <p>Since then the competition has  become a tradition in Washington state for the Chinese language learning community. 
               Students throughout the states participated to show their knowledge and talent in Chinese Language and Chinese culture. 
               Each competition draws hundreds of students and the teachers.  This event greatly promotes the Chinese learningIin Washington State.</p>
             <br/>
             <p>To continue this great tradition, the Little Masters Club worked closely with other participating organizations 
                and completed the transition of leadership in 2020.  Today we are happy to announce 2020 Washington State Chinese Language 
                and Talent Competition is open for registration. K to 12th Grade students in both public and private schools of Washington 
                State as well as those from Chinese heritage schools and home children institutes are welcome to participate. we hope this 
                event will provide a venue where students with diverse cultural backgrounds get together to share their knowledge and experience.</p>
            ]]>
          </text>
        </paragraph>
      </article>
      <article title="Objective">
        <paragraph indent="false">
          <item>To acknowledge and reward the achievements of the students and teachers in learning Chinese.</item>
          <item>To provide a positive venue for students with diverse backgrounds to come together and share knowledge of Chinese culture and Chinese learning experience.</item>
        </paragraph>
      </article>
      <article title="Competition Levels &amp; Categories">
        <paragraph indent="false">
          <text>
            <![CDATA[
                <p><b>We divide the Chinese Talent Competition into following grade levels:</b></p>
                <br />
                <p>Lower Elementary (Grades K-2) 小学低年级组</p>
                <p>Upper Elementary (Grades 3-5) 小学中高年级组</p>
                <p>Middle School (Grades 6-8) 初中组</p>
                <p>High School (Grades 9-12) 高中组</p>
                <br />
                <p><b>Here is a list of the availabe competitions:</b></p>
                <br />
                <p>Group Poetry Recitation 團體詩詞朗誦</p>
                <p>Individual Poetry Recitation 個人詩詞朗誦</p>
                <p>Group Talent Show  團體才藝競賽</p>
   		<p>Individual Talent Show  個人才藝競賽</p>
                <p>Group Chinese Singing  團體歌唱比賽</p>
                <p>Individual Chinese Singing  個人歌唱比賽</p>
                <p>Language Art 口语才艺竟赛</p>
                <p>Story Telling 說故事</p>
                <p>Public Speaking 演講</p>
                <p>Drawing 繪畫比賽</p>
                <p>Chinese Chess 象棋</p>
                <p>China Knowledge Bowl  中國常識競答</p>
                <br />
            ]]>
          </text>
        </paragraph>
      </article>
      <article title="Awards">
        <paragraph indent="false">
          <text>
            <![CDATA[
              <p>All contestants can pick up a commemorate gift at the assignment center on the same day for their participation in the competition. The top three in each competition will receive scholarships ($50 for individual contestants and $100 for team contestants) and awards from the World Languages Division of the OSPI.  </p>
              </br> 
              <p>The awards ceremony will be held at the auditorium of the Chief Sealth International High School at 2:30 pm on the day of the competition.  Families and friends in the community are welcome to attend the awards ceremony. </p>
            ]]>
          </text>
        </paragraph>
      </article>
    </articles>
    <sideBar>
      <videoClips header="Competition Videos">
        <videoClip title="" clipUrl="https://www.youtube.com/embed/OHzx9QaPPDQ" />
        <videoClip title="" clipUrl="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NLXBOQO-qnc" />
      </videoClips>
      <relatedLinks header="2020 Event Organizers&lt;br/&gt;主辦單位">
        <!--<relatedLink iconUrl="/Images/pin.png" title="Cultural Exploration of Greater China Foundation&lt;br/&gt;中華文化之旅基金會" linkUrl="/public/home.html" />-->
        <relatedLink iconUrl="/Images/pin.png" title="Little Masters Club&lt;br/&gt;小大师俱乐部" linkUrl="http://littlemasterswa.azurewebsites.net" target="_blank" />
      </relatedLinks>
      <relatedLinks header="Proudly Sponsored By&lt;br/&gt;赞助单位">
        <relatedLink iconUrl="/Images/pin.png" title="Confucius Institute of the State of Washington&lt;br/&gt;華州孔子學院" linkUrl="http://confucius.washington.edu" target="_blank" />
        <relatedLink iconUrl="/Images/pin.png" title="Chinese Language Teachers Association Washington State&lt;br/&gt;華州中文教師學會" linkUrl="http://www.clta-wa.org" target="_blank" />
        <relatedLink iconUrl="/Images/pin.png" title="Chief Sealth International High School (CSIHS) &lt;br/&gt;希尔斯国际高中" linkUrl="http://chiefsealthhs.seattleschools.org/" target="_blank" />
        <relatedLink iconUrl="/Images/pin.png" title="Office of Superintendent of Public Instruction World Languages Program&lt;br/&gt;華州教育部世界語言組" linkUrl="http://www.k12.wa.us/WorldLanguages/" target="_blank" />
      </relatedLinks>
    </sideBar>
  </page>
</ce>