<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<ce>
  <journey title="Trent Wieburg 2013" align="left" rootUrl="/Content/Tours/Journey/2013/TrentWieburg">
    <bio>
      <name first="Trent" last="Wieburg" display="Trent Wieburg" />
      <email></email>
      <phone></phone>
      <address></address>
      <city>Snoqualmie</city>
      <state>WA</state>
      <school>Mount Si High School</school>
      <grade>10</grade>
      <subject>Social Studies</subject>
      <year>2013</year>
      <photo>/content/tours/journey/2013/TrentWieburg/photos/TrentWieburg.jpg</photo>
      <about>
        <![CDATA[
        Born in central Illinois, Trent grew up in Silverdale, WA on the Kitsap Peninsula.  He developed his passion for Social Studies thanks to his 
        fantastic Advanced Placement teachers at Central Kitsap High School- Pam Galvani and Sarah Fisher.  Trent continued his interest in Social 
        Studies at the University of Washington where he earned two Bachelor of Arts degrees in History and Political Science with a minor in Art History.  
        During his time at UW, Trent developed an interest for overseas travel while attending the Italian Studies program at the UW Rome Center in Italy.  
        Trent decided to pursue a career in high school teaching during his experiences tutoring at Franklin and Garfield High Schools in Seattle.  
        He graduated from the UW Masters in Teaching program in 2008.
        <br/><br/>
        After completing student teaching experiences at Lindbergh High School in Renton, Mountlake Terrace High School, and the Trondheim International 
        School in Norway, Trent began his public school teaching career at Shelton High School.  Trent currently teaches Social Studies at Mount Si 
        High School in Snoqualmie, WA.  His recent teaching assignments include: AP American Government and Politics, AP Comparative Government 
        (China is one of the six focus countries), Contemporary World Problems, World History, World Geography, and Psychology.  In his free time, 
        Trent enjoys traveling, attending UW football and Seattle Sounders soccer games, golfing, hiking, and spending time with friends and family.  
        He is very excited and honored to be participating in the CE program and this will be his first travel experience in Asia.
        ]]>
      </about>
    </bio>
    <album folder="Photos" align="right">
    </album>
    <diary>
      <articles>
      </articles>
    </diary>
    <teachingPlan>
      <articles>
        <article title="Comparing US and Taiwan’s Secondary School Systems">
          <paragraph>
            <text>
              <![CDATA[
                <div><a style="color:blue;" href="/documents/tours/Trent Wieburg China Lesson Plans.pdf" target="_blank">Please click this link to see Trent's lesson plan.</a></div>
              ]]>
            </text>
          </paragraph>
        </article>
      </articles>
    </teachingPlan>
  </journey>
</ce>