<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<ce>
  <tour>
    <articles>
      <article title="Background">
        <paragraph>
          <text>
            <![CDATA[
            <p>The Cultural Exploration(CE)of Greater China Foundation is a community-based non-profit organization dedicated to promote a
            better understanding of greater China and Chinese culture through education by offering cultural learning opportunities to
            schools or other educational institutions. In the past ten years, through generous donations from local communities and
            businesses, CE has sponsored over 40 teachers to tour China, Hong Kong, and Taiwan. This year, through successful
            fund-raising, we are pleased to offer this great travel opportunity again to teachers that are enthusiastic about
            bringing China and Chinese culture to their classrooms.</p>
            <br/>
            <p>Unlike other cultural exchange programs sponsored by various governments or academic organizations, CE is a community-based
            program. We believe that the most effective way to know modern day China, Chinese Culture and people is through pressure-free
            interpersonal interactions.</p>
            ]]>
          </text>
        </paragraph>
      </article>
      <article title="Objective">
        <paragraph indent="false">
          <text>
            Today, Chinese people live in different parts of the world and Chinese culture is manifested in a variety of ways. The
            objective of this program is to assist American teachers to:
          </text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph indent="true">
          <item>Introduce greater China to their students with accurate information, confidence and authority.</item>
          <item>Develop teaching plans to enhance curriculum related to China, Pacific Rim and Asia.</item>
          <item>Inspire students to learn about China and Chinese culture.</item>
          <item>Have a better understanding of Americans with Chinese heritage.</item>
        </paragraph>
      </article>
      <article title="Cultural Exploration Trip Outline">
        <paragraph indent="false">
          <text>
            To optimize the tour experience and align with the cultural exchange objective, the trip provides two distinct focuses:
          </text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph indent="true">
          <text>
            <![CDATA[
            <b>Managed Tour:</b> A commercially managed sightseeing tour to historical landmarks such as the Great Wall, the Forbidden City and the Terra Cotta
            Warriors and visits to modern cities such as Shanghai, Hong Kong and Taipei. It is fast-paced and well structured. The tour
            guides provide informative narrations on history and geography.
            ]]>
          </text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph indent="true">
          <text>
          <![CDATA[
          <b>Local Host Family:</b> Host-family sponsored programs provide opportunities to interact with Chinese families, teachers and students on an informal
          basis. Unlike the sightseeing tour, this emphasizes the understanding of modern day Chinese family living, school
          systems and cultural exchange. This includes school visits in Shanghai and Taipei. The participating teachers will have an
          opportunity to exchange teaching philosophies with Chinese educators and conduct teaching demonstration in local schools.
          ]]>
          </text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph indent="true">
          <text>
          <![CDATA[
          <b>Time & Place:</b> The trip will take place in the summer of 2013: Tentatively from late July through early August for about two
          weeks. While every year s trip is planned independently, the trip generally includes major cities such as <i>Beijing, Xian,
          Shanghai, Hong Kong and Taipei</i>. Other cities may be added depending on each year s focus.
          ]]>
          </text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph indent="true">
          <text>
          <![CDATA[
          <b>Expenses covered by CE:</b> Airfare, land transportation, lodging & meals. Expenses not covered by CE: personal expenses including but 
				  not limited to visa fee, excess baggage charge, telephone expenses, gifts for the host families and tips for tour guides and drivers.
          ]]>
          </text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph indent="true">
          <text>
            <![CDATA[
            <b>Logistics:</b> Summer in these parts of Asia is extremely hot and humid. Average temperatures easily reach 100 F  with 50% or
            greater humidity. A typical day during the trip involves 12 to 14 hours of activities including travel from place to place on a
            tour bus. Consideration for the physical and mental preparedness, key to a successful trip in a foreign land, is
            highly encouraged.
            ]]>
          </text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph indent="true">
          <text>
            <![CDATA[
            <b>Continuing Education Credits:</b> Several teachers in the past have successfully applied and earned up to <u>70 clock hours</u> or <u>7
            continuing education credits</u> for the CE Tour through Seattle University. Interested teachers will be responsible for
            completing the necessary application form and coordinating with CE.
            ]]>
          </text>
        </paragraph>
      </article>
    </articles>
    <sideBar>
      <relatedLinks header="More Tours...">
        <relatedLink iconUrl="/Images/at.png" title="2012 Tours" linkUrl="/public/articles/cearticle.aspx?theme=blue&amp;tag=tour&amp;path=/tours&amp;content=cetour.xml&amp;page=cetour.html" />
        <relatedLink iconUrl="/Images/at.png" title="2011 Tours" linkUrl="/public/articles/cearticle.aspx?theme=blue&amp;tag=tour&amp;path=/tours&amp;content=cetour.xml&amp;page=cetour.html" />
        <relatedLink iconUrl="/Images/at.png" title="2010 Tours" linkUrl="/public/articles/cearticle.aspx?theme=blue&amp;tag=tour&amp;path=/tours&amp;content=cetour.xml&amp;page=cetour.html" />
        <relatedLink iconUrl="/Images/at.png" title="2009 Tours" linkUrl="/public/articles/cearticle.aspx?theme=blue&amp;tag=tour&amp;path=/tours&amp;content=cetour.xml&amp;page=cetour.html" />
      </relatedLinks>
      <barTiles>
        <barTile caption="The image has a link" imageUrl="/Images/Tours/citystreet.jpg" linkUrl="/Public/Home.aspx" captionPosition="bottom" />
        <barTile caption="&lt;b&gt;This is a bold caption&lt;/b&gt;" imageUrl="/Images/Tours/scenery2.jpg" linkUrl="" captionPosition="bottom" />
        <barTile caption="&lt;i&gt;This is an italic caption that is a bit longer&lt;/i&gt;" imageUrl="/Images/Tours/scenery1.jpg" linkUrl="" captionPosition="bottom" />
      </barTiles>
      <testimonies header="Testimonies">
        <testimory caption="Jimmy, Redmond 2012:" text="Cultural Exploration provides me a real opportunity to export China culture." iconUrl="/Images/talk.png" linkUrl="/public/Testimony.aspx?id=jimmy" captionPosition="top" />
        <testimory caption="Amy, Seattle 2011:" text="I met a lot of people down in the alley who share the real Chinese story." iconUrl="/Images/colorpen.png" linkUrl="/public/Testimony.aspx?id=amy" captionPosition="top" />
      </testimonies>
    </sideBar>
  </tour>
</ce>