<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<ce>
  <journey title="Camilla Schulte 2015" align="left" rootUrl="/Content/Tours/Journey/2015/CamillaSchulte">
    <bio>
      <name first="Camilla" last="Schulte" display="Camilla Schulte" />
      <email>cschulte@lwsd.org</email>
      <phone></phone>
      <address></address>
      <city></city>
      <state></state>
      <school>Carl Sandburg Elementary, Lake Washington</school>
      <grade>K-5</grade>
      <subject>Library</subject>
      <year>2015</year>
      <photo>/content/tours/journey/2015/CamillaSchulte/photos/CamillaSchulte.jpg</photo>
      <about>
        <![CDATA[
        My name is Camilla Schulte and I am an elementary librarian in the Lake Washington School District. I am thrilled that I have the opportunity to visit China in the 2015 CE tour and am very grateful that the Cultural Exploration of Greater China made this possible.</br></br>
		I grew up in South Texas and satisfied my wanderlust by becoming a voracious reader. I traveled a bit as I became older, but focused mainly on my studies. I have a Bachelor in English Teaching and a Masters of Library and Informational Science. Once in my library classroom, I discovered a passion for not only connecting my students with quality stories that both inform and entertain them, but also for engaging students through new multimedia, book talks, and creating videos using a green screen. I also endeavor to make the worlds of stories come alive by frequently wearing costumes and creating fun, interactive displays.</br></br>
		One of the best ways students can expand their perspectives is to read the story of another child from another culture. I am currently working to extend our collection to include culturally diverse children's literature. I would love to augment their reading experiences with real-life information I have learned firsthand through your program.</br></br>
		When I heard about this opportunity, I jumped at the chance to apply because it directly aligns with my goals. I want to be connected with like-minded colleagues so that I can continue to have meaningful discussion about celebrating multicultural differences inside the classroom. I feel that incorporating Chinese culture will enrich the curriculum and help my students to make cross-cultural connections with their peers at school and around the world.</br></br>
		When I am not teaching or reading, I enjoy trying out new recipes, hiking, and running. I have run a few half-marathons, and this year I am running the 200-mile Ragnar Relay with a team of twelve. Recently I also discovered two new passions; I have learned how to make and edit videos and I am taking pottery classes, where I learn wheel-throwing and hand-building.</br></br>
		I feel that most of what I do when I’m not teaching always helps center me when I come back to the classroom. I will always keep searching for new ways to engage and enlighten my students, which is why I am so honored and excited for this marvelous travel experience. 
        ]]>
      </about>
    </bio>
    <album folder="Photos" align="right">
      <summary>
      </summary>
    </album>
    <diary>
      <articles>
      </articles>
    </diary>
    <teachingPlan>
      <articles>
      </articles>
    </teachingPlan>
    <testimony title="">
    </testimony>
    <videoClips>
    </videoClips>
  </journey>
</ce>