<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<ce>
  <page>
    <articles>
      <article title="Support Us">
        <paragraph>
          <text>
            <![CDATA[
              <div>Cultural Exploration of Greater China Foundation completed two very successful events in 2013 thanks to many tireless volunteers 
                   and generous donors.</div><br/>
            ]]>
          </text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph indent="false">
          <item>
            <![CDATA[
            <b>The Chinese Language and Talent Competition</b> in March was a sounding success. Over 480 students from 110 schools across Washington
            State participated in this event. Superintendent Dorn attended the award ceremony praising this outstanding community effort
            supporting education and cultural exchange.<div style="height:5px"></div>
            ]]>
          </item>
          <item>
            <![CDATA[
            5 talented teachers from the greater Seattle area participated in this year’s <b>Cultural Exploration Tour</b>. They not only visited
            experimental schools, traditional schools and schools for under-privileged students in Beijing, Shanghai and Taipei, they were able
            to experience the daily lives in these modern cities with many host families.
            ]]>
          </item>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph>
          <text>
            <![CDATA[
              The students and teachers attended the Chinese Language & Talent Competition are preparing and looking forward to next year’s competition. 
              The Cultural Exploration teachers are networking with their colleagues and schools to bring more teachers to take next year’s tour.
            ]]>
          </text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph>
          <text>
            To continue these worthy activities, we need your continuing support. There are some options for your consideration:
          </text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph indent="false">
          <item>Volunteer your time, be part of the CE team</item>
          <item>Make a personal donation online using PayPal</item>
          <item>Check with your employer on Corporate Matching Fund</item>
          <item>Become a Corporate Sponsor</item>
          <item>Attend our annual Friendship Luncheon  Fundraiser in September</item>
        </paragraph>
      </article>
    </articles>
    <sideBar>
      <relatedLinks header="2014 Events">
        <relatedLink iconUrl="/Images/pin.png" title="2014 Friendship Luncheon Invitation Letter" linkUrl="/documents/support/2014 Fiendship Luncheon.pdf" target="_blank" />
      </relatedLinks>
      <videoClips header="Tour Videos">
        <videoClip title="" clipUrl="https://www.youtube.com/embed/cnG_hEaQdgg" />
      </videoClips>
      <!--<barTiles>
        <barTile caption="For Students" imageUrl="/images/home/tile/TalentAwardCeremony.jpg" linkUrl="/public/talent/cetalent.html" captionPosition="bottom" />
        <barTile caption="For Teachers" imageUrl="/images/home/tile/DandelionSchool.jpg" linkUrl="/public/tours/cetour.html" captionPosition="bottom" />
        <barTile caption="For the Community" imageUrl="/images/home/tile/DandelionschoolBeijing.jpg" linkUrl="" captionPosition="bottom" />
      </barTiles>-->
    </sideBar>
  </page>
</ce>