<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<ce>
  <page>
    <articles>
      <article title="Date and Location 举办日期/地点 ">
        <paragraph indent="false">
          <text>
            <![CDATA[
            <b>Date 日期:</b>
            <br/>
            <b>Sunday, May 3, 2020</b>
	    		  <br/>
            <b>Competition Time:8:30am – 2:30pm </b> <br/>
            <b>Awards  Ceremony:2:30pm - 3:30pm </b><br/>  
            <b>(Please see "Schedule 比赛时间表" on the right hand panel for detailed event schedule.)</b>
            <br/><br/>
            ]]>
          </text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph indent="false">
          <text>
            <![CDATA[
            <b>Location 地点:</b> 
	          <br/>
            <b>Chief Sealth International High School</b>
            <br/>
            <i>https://chiefsealthhs.seattleschools.org/</i>
            <br/>
            2600 SW Thistle Street
            <br/>
            Seattle, WA 98126
            <br/><br/>
            ]]>
          </text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph indent="false">
          <text>
            <![CDATA[
            <b>Awards 奖励:</b> 
            <br/>
	          All contestants can pick up a commemorate gift at the assignment center on the same day
for their participation in the competition. The top three in each competition will receive
scholarships ($50 for individual contestants and $100 for team contestants) and awards from
the World Languages Division of the OSPI.  
              <br/><br/>
			The awards ceremony will be held at the <b>auditorium of the Chief Sealth International High 
			School</b> at 2:30pm on the day of the competition. Families and friends in the community are welcome 
			to attend the awards ceremony. 
			<br/><br/>
            ]]>
          </text>
        </paragraph>
      </article>
      <article title="Registration Information">
        <paragraph indent="false">
          <text>
            <![CDATA[
            <b>Registration Deadline 报名截止日期:</b>
            <br/>
	          <b>Monday, April 13, 2020</b>
	          The registration is first-come-first-serve.  
	          No late application will be accepted.
	          <br/><br/>  
            ]]>
          </text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph indent="false">
          <text>
            <![CDATA[
            <b>Registration 报名方法:</b> 
            <br/>
            To register, please click on the tag “2020 Registration” at https://littlemastersclub.org/clatc/.
            <br/><br/>
            Participants will receive an automatic confirmation by email upon completing the registration process. 
            <b>Please bring a copy of this confirmation email to the competition for check-in. </b>
            <br/><br/>
            ]]>
          </text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph indent="false">
          <text>
            <![CDATA[
            <b>Registration Fee 报名费:</b> 
            <br/>
 Registration fee is $10 per person per number of competitions (individual or team) entered (entering one competition is $10, two will be $20, three will be $30, so on and so forth). The registration fee must be paid on-line by using PayPal when registering.
 <br/><br/>
 Please note that the registration fee can be waived for participants on subsidized school meal plans. To apply, please download the form "Fee Waiver 减免报名费" on the right hand panel for details.)
           <br/><br/>
            ]]>
          </text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph indent="false">
          <text>
            <![CDATA[
            <b>Withdrawal 取消报名:</b> 
            <br/>
If the cancellation is made before the registration deadline (April 13, 2020), the registration
fee will be refunded after deducting 40% of the handling fee. If the cancellation is made
after the registration deadline (April 13, 2020), it will not be refunded.
           <br/><br/> ]]>
          </text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph indent="false">
          <text>
            <![CDATA[
            <b>Competition Class 比赛分级:</b> 
            <br/>
				Please note that Individual Language-Based competitions (i.e. Individual Poetry Recitation/
个人诗歌朗诵, Story Telling/说故事 and Public Speaking/演讲) are divided into the
following three subcategories according to the student’s language level (rather than the
student's family background). These competitions are offered to learners who speak Chinese
as a second language. If you are from a native-speaking country, and you still use Chinese
as your first language, please do not sign up for these competitions. <br/><br />
            <ul>
              <li><b>Class A: </b> A contest of this level is for students who have advanced Chinese proficiency (or
the first-place winner in a Class B contest from last year). They already
accurately grasp the Chinese pronunciation and can use Chinese skillfully. Such
students may have lived or vacationed in a country that uses Chinese and they
have opportunity to communicate or learn in Chinese outside the classroom with
other people (such as parents or relatives).<br/><br/>
Note: The winners of the first place in the class A contests from last year can
NOT sign up for the same competition. </li><br/>
              <li><b>Class B: </b> A contest of this level is for learners who have moderate Chinese proficiency (or
the first-place winner in the class C contest from last year). Students competing at
this level are well-spoken in Chinese, but they are still interfered by factors such
as mother tongue or dialect in words or pronunciation. </li><br/>
              <li><b>Class C: </b> A contest of this level is for students who are beginners in Chinese proficiency.
We encouraged those to compete at this level if they are not yet proficient in
using Chinese to do daily conversations and find Chinese oral presentation a big
challenge.</li>
            </ul>
            <br/>
            ***Please note that the judges have the authority of promoting students in the Class B or C
contests whose Chinese language skills are much higher than the level’s expectation to
compete again at a higher level and the scores that they have earned at the previous level
will be voided. Please kindly respect judges’ decisions. <mark>The list of students who are
promoted to compete in Class A or B will be posted at the administration office. Please be
sure to check the list after completion of the contest.</mark> 
            <br/><br/>
            *** If a student is not sure about which level of competition to register for, please consult
with their Chinese language teachers or the event organizer whose Contact Information is
provided at the end of this guide.
           <br/><br/> ]]>
          </text>
        </paragraph>
       <paragraph indent="false">
          <text>
            <![CDATA[
            <b>Competition Restriction 比赛资格限制</b> <br>
	    <ul>
	    <li>Any individual or group who had won the first place in a contest before (except the
China Knowledge Bowl) needs to take one year’s gap before signing up for the same
contest at the same level. The participants of the China Knowledge Bowl are not under
this restriction, which is to say, they can sign up at the same level under the same grade
range regardless of their places in the past. Individuals or groups who won the first
place are encouraged to participate in a higher-level contest. For example: winners of
the Class B Language contests can participate in a Class A Language contest; or the
Grades K-2 winners may take the challenge to participate in the Grades 3-5 contest and
so on. <br/><br/>
<br /><li>In a team competition, students from a lower-grade level can join the team at a higher
grade level, i.e. Grades K-2 students can join a Grades 3-5 team, but not vice versa, i.e.
Grades 3-5 students cannot join a Grades K-2 team.</li>
<br /><li>The competition of Chinese Chess now only has only two grade category: the level of
High School (Grades 9 – 12) and the level of Middle School (Grades 6-8). But
contestants from Lower Elementary (Grades K-2) and Higher Elementary (Grades 3-5)
can sign up to compete at the Middle School or the High School level.</li>
<br /><li>No contestant can participate in the contest of the same category more than once, except
for the Poetry Recitation. For example, if a contestant signs up to compete as an
individual or in a group in the Singing contest (歌唱比赛), he/she cannot sign up to
compete in another group or for another performer even as a background singer or as
help with a musical instrument. However, contestants in the Individual Poetry
Recitation (个人诗歌朗诵) can participate in a Group Poetry Recitation just once.</li>
<br /><li>In order to develop students' ability to participate independently, parents or teachers are
prohibited from offering any assistance or hint to the contestants on the side during their
competition. Violators will be disqualified.</li>
	    </ul>
            <br>
 	      ]]>
          </text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph indent="false">
          <text>
            <![CDATA[
            <b>Contact Information 询问处:</b> 
            <br/>
            If you have any questions regarding the competition or need more information, please email <i>cltc@littlemastersclub.org</i>.
            ]]>
          </text>
        </paragraph>
      </article>
    </articles>
    <sideBar includeLinks="true" includeTiles="false" includeVideos="false" includeTestimonies="false">
      <includeLinks path="/content/talent/guidelines/relatedlinks.xml"/>
    </sideBar>
  </page>
</ce>