<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<ce>
  <journey title="Annie John 2013" align="left" rootUrl="/Content/Tours/Journey/2013/AnnieJohn">
    <bio>
      <name first="Annie" last="John" display="Annie John" />
      <email></email>
      <phone></phone>
      <address></address>
      <city></city>
      <state></state>
      <school>Federal Way</school>
      <grade>2/3</grade>
      <subject>General</subject>
      <year>2013</year>
      <photo>/content/tours/journey/2013/AnnieJohn/photos/AnnieJohn.jpg</photo>
      <about>
        <![CDATA[
        Hello!  I am Annie John, and I am blessed to have the opportunity to represent the CE Foundation on this journey.  It is an experience that 
        I will carry with me in both my personal and professional life.
        <br/><br/>
        I currently teach a 2/3 Highly Capable class in the Federal Way School District, and truly love my job.  I am fortunate to be able to have a 
        huge impact on these future leaders of America.  Prior to leading the HiCap program, I taught fifth grade for five years.  In addition to my 
        classroom position, I also serve on the school and district leadership boards.  Through the Highly Capable leadership team, I am able to serve 
        students on a larger scale and impact the educational community from within. 
        <br/><br/>
        Over the past few years, our schools have become more culturally diverse, and will continue to grow in this direction.  Building relationships 
        with students is one of the core focuses of my teaching philosophy – and I believe that we must understand a child’s cultural background in order 
        to fully bridge together the relationship.  Having little background in Chinese culture, I am thrilled to have the opportunity to learn through 
        experience, the impact Chinese history and culture has on daily life.
        <br/><br/>
        When I am not in my classroom, I am working on my PhD at the University of Washington.  In addition, my daughter and I love to take day trips to 
        obscure farmers markets, hike, travel, and read.  I am looking forward to sharing this summer’s experiences with my students in hopes that it 
        inspires them to learn more about the remarkable Chinese culture
        ]]>
      </about>
    </bio>
    <album folder="Photos" align="right">
    </album>
    <diary>
      <articles>
      </articles>
    </diary>
    <teachingPlan>
      <articles>
        <article title="The MYSTERY of HISTORY - A unit on China">
          <paragraph>
            <text>
              <![CDATA[
                <div><a style="color:blue;" href="/Documents/Tours/Prelim Plan - Annie John - FULL UNIT.pdf" target="_blank">Please click this link to see Annie's preliminary lesson plan.</a></div>
              ]]>
            </text>
          </paragraph>
        </article>
      </articles>
    </teachingPlan>
    <testimony title="What an experience!">
    </testimony>
    <videoClips>
    </videoClips>
  </journey>
</ce>