<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<ce>
  <journey title="Andrea Gardner 2015" align="left" rootUrl="/Content/Tours/Journey/2015/AndreaGardner">
    <bio>
      <name first="Andrea" last="Gardner" display="Andrea Gardner" />
      <email>andrea.gardner@highlineschools.org</email>
      <phone></phone>
      <address></address>
      <city></city>
      <state></state>
      <school>White Center Heights Elementary</school>
      <grade>K-6</grade>
      <subject>Extended Day Outcomes Coordinator</subject>
      <year>2015</year>
      <photo>/content/tours/journey/2015/AndreaGardner/photos/AndreaGardner.jpg</photo>
      <about>
        <![CDATA[
        My name is Andrea Gardner, I am an educator in Washington State.  My current position is very unique: as the Extended Day Outcomes Coordinator at White Center Heights Elementary, I have worked to create, grow, and sustain an after-school program.  The major aspects include knowing students and families in order to provide the precisely desired activities to promote academic and social/emotional success.  Through community collaboration, grant writing, and collaboration with teachers, I have gained traction in offering free programs to nearly 325 of our 600 K-6 students at White Center Heights Elementary.</br></br>
		I grew up in the great state of Maine and in pursuit of Ancient Mesoamerican knowledge, I ended up in Seattle.  It took me a wonderful 13 years to get through my undergraduate and graduate degrees.  Between traveling and acquiring far too many credits, I finally landed on Education as my focus (and I LOVE it!).  I have had many careers including: Photographer, Web/Graphic Designer, and Professional Jump-Roper.  I have travelled throughout Mexico and Italy studying ancient civilizations while teaching English and Jump Roping.  For the past 3 years motherhood has taken over as my primary responsibility, ambition, and passion.  My daughter is 3-years old and very excited to go to Maine while mom goes to China!</br></br>
		My excitement for this trip stems from my passion for education and travel.  After speaking with the other teachers at my school, I am even more excited for this trip.  I have their full support, encouragement, and excitement pushing me to learn and bring back exciting first-hand knowledge to share.  I feel like I am truly representing the entire school and seeking information for ALL students and teachers.</br></br>
		I look forward to creating dynamic lesson plans and being an active participant in the Cultural Explorations family for this summer and beyond!  I’ve already started packing!
        ]]>
      </about>
    </bio>
    <album folder="Photos" align="right">
      <summary>
        <![CDATA[

        ]]>
      </summary>
    </album>
    <diary>
      <articles>
      </articles>
    </diary>
    <teachingPlan>
      <articles>
      </articles>
    </teachingPlan>
    <testimony title="">
    </testimony>
    <videoClips>
    </videoClips>
  </journey>
</ce>