<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<ce>
  <journey title="Monica DeWald 2014" align="left" rootUrl="/Content/Tours/Journey/2014/MonicaDeWald">
    <bio>
      <name first="Monica" last="DeWald" display="Monica DeWald" />
      <email></email>
      <phone></phone>
      <address></address>
      <city></city>
      <state></state>
      <school>Seattle World School</school>
      <grade>High School</grade>
      <subject>Language Arts</subject>
      <year>2014</year>
      <photo>/content/tours/journey/2014/MonicaDeWald/photos/MonicaDeWald.png</photo>
      <about>
        <![CDATA[
        I’m Monica DeWald, and I teach High School Language Arts and Literacy 1 at Seattle World School in the Seattle Public School District. 
		I am so happy to be selected for this year’s CE China trip!<br/><br/>
		The school where I teach is aimed at helping new immigrants and students who want to increase their English proficiency in a multicultural 
		setting. Our school is home to students from many backgrounds, countries and language groups. Because there are a number of Chinese students 
		at our school, I have been working hard to get more acquainted with their language and culture. This past year, I have taken Mandarin Chinese 
		lessons and have participated in a number of meetups and community events to try and better understand my students and their transition to 
		American culture and schooling.<br/><br/>
		I believe that this trip to China and Taiwan will help me get a better picture of my students’ lives before SWS and will help me to better 
		serve the multicultural population at my school and in Seattle. Additionally, during this trip, I hope to practice my Chinese, try new foods, 
		meet new people and learn new things about China’s great history and culture.<br/><br/> 
		In my life outside school, I like to do yoga, dance, go for walks, and discover new places with my friends and family
        ]]>
      </about>
    </bio>
    <album folder="Photos" align="right">
      <summary>
        <![CDATA[
        Instead of sharing her photos, Monica published a <a href="/content/tours/journey/2014/MonicaDeWald/MonicaTripReviewJournal.docx" target="_blank">Trip Journal</a> with embedded pictures, which are extracted below. 
        She talked about her favorite things in each city, with representative pictures covering the scenic walks, 
        memorable moments, and the fun meetings/dinners with students, friends, and host families in multiple locations.  
        What do you think her <i>aha</i> moments are?  Those are listed near the end of her journal.  Read on.<br/><br/>
        Monica also produced a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NS5uPtfm0_s" target="_blank">short video</a> to 
        introduce the 2104 teachers’ experience with the CE Tour.        
        ]]>
      </summary>
    </album>
    <diary>
      <articles>
      </articles>
    </diary>
    <teachingPlan>
      <articles>
        <article title="Cultural Change in a Globaling World">
          <paragraph>
            <text>
              <![CDATA[
              <div>
                Monica developed this <a style="color:blue;" href="/content/tours/journey/2014/MonicaDeWald/Monica Lesson Plan.pdf" target="_blank">Lesson Plan</a> for her High School <i>Language Arts & Social Studies</i> class.
              </div>
              ]]>
            </text>
          </paragraph>
        </article>
      </articles>
    </teachingPlan>
    <testimony title="What an experience!">
    </testimony>
    <videoClips>
    </videoClips>
  </journey>
</ce>